https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
Lovely fleeting afternoon, Marcelka.
Krásné prchavé odpoledne, Marcelko.
Sorry I'm late.
Omlouvám se za zpoždění.
I don't feel like going out in this weather anyway.
Stejně se mi do toho nečasu nechce.
But it's nice and warm in here.
Ale máme tady teplíčko.
Were you grilling a goose in the storeroom again, Ozzak?
Negriloval jsi zas, Ozzáku, v kumbále husu?
I wasn't.
Negriloval.
Did you come straight here?
Jeli jste rovnou?
He wasn't here at all.
Vůbec tu nebyl.
That's a relief.
To se mi ulevilo.
For me too, actually.
Mně vlastně taky.
Oh, the mail lady stopped by.
Jo, stavila se tu pošťačka.
You have a registered letter.
Máte tu rekomando.
She gave it to you?
Ona vám ho dala?
I can do your signature.
Umím váš podpis.
And she didn't notice you're not me?
A ona nepoznala, že nejste já?
She didn't care.
Bylo jí to jedno.
Here, it's from the electric company.
Tady, je to z elektrických podniků.
I sense a strange tension from it.
Cítím z něj podivné napětí.
That was good.
To bylo dobrý.
It was, it was.
Bylo, bylo.
So I'm going to close up for today.
Tak já už pro dnešek zavřu.
What do you say?
Co říkáte?
I hope not.
Snad ne.
Fine, I'll wait until six, but nobody's coming anyway.
Tak dobře, no tak já počkám do šesti, ale stejně už nikdo nepřijde.
Six thousand.
Šest tisíc.
Of what?
Čeho?
We owe a surcharge for electricity.
Máme doplatek za elektriku.
I don't understand.
No to nechápu.
What does Ozzak grill his goose on?
Na čem si Ozzák griluje tu husu?
On a grill.
Na grillu.
Electric or gas?
Ale elektrickým nebo plynovým?
Charcoal.
Na dřevěném uhlí.
But I don't make that many calls.
Ale já netelefonuju moc.
I call a perfectly normal amount.
Teď volám úplně normálně.
We'll talk about this later.
Ještě si o tom promluvíme.
Ozzak, how come you weren't in the shop?
Ozzáku, jak to, že jsi nebyl v krámě?
Bro, you're not going to believe what you're about to hear.
Brácha, tomu, co budeš slyšet, nebudeš věřit.
Make it short.
Zkrať to.
I was drinking.
Chlastal jsem.
Tomorrow you've got a full day shift.
Zítra máš celodenní.
Great, at least I'll get some sleep.
Super, aspoň se vyspím.
You sleep all the time.
Vždyť spíš pořád.
But I don't sleep that much.
Ale já nespím moc.
I sleep a normal amount.
Spím úplně normálně.
We'll talk about this later.
Ještě si o tom promluvíme.
Sit down.
Sednout.
Meeting.
Porada.
We have to start saving.
Musíme začít šetřit.
And because of that we have to sit at home all evening?
A kvůli tomu jako musíme sedět celý večer doma?
During the best time of day?
V tu nejlepší denní dobu?
Yes, we have to.
Ano, musíme.
We have a six thousand crown electricity surcharge.
Máme šest tisíc nedoplatek za elektriku.
Don't you have six thousand under the table?
Nemáš šest tisíc načerno?
Don't make light of it.
Ty nezlehčuj to.
I've decided we won't touch our savings.
Rozhodl jsem se, že nebudeme sahat na úspory.
So what are you going to pay it with?
A z čeho to teda zaplatíš?
That's exactly the point.
A to je přesně ono.
You spend it and I pay for it.
Tak vy to utratíte a já to zaplatím.
How do we spend it?
Jak utratíme?
For example, I've already bought you a new phone credit three times this month.
Tak například tobě jsem tenhle měsíc už třikrát kupoval novej kredit.
I thought we were talking about electricity.
Já myslela, že se bavíme o elektrice.
We're talking about money.
Bavíme se o penězích.
And a phone eats money.
A mobil žere peníze.
I'm off then.
Tak já jdu.
I've got no money, I don't ride a phone, nor the tram.
Peníze nemám, mobilem nejezdím, elektrikou taky ne.
You can't save on me.
Na mě se šetřit nedá.
I'm free.
Já jsem zadarmo.
Free?
Zadarmo?
What about your bar tab?
A co tvoje útrata v hospodě?
Did Simona say something?
Simona něco říkala?
I'm already paying for it.
Už teď to platím.
Oh right, actually.
A jo, vlastně.
Too bad you can't save on that.
Škoda, že na tom se šetřit nedá.
You can.
Dá.
You can?
Dá?
Yes, you can.
Ano, dá.
If you have one less beer a day, we'll save 7,000 crowns a year.
Když si každej den dáš o jedno pivo míň, ušetříme za rok 7000 Kč.
I'm supposed to have only thirteen a day?
To si mám jako denně dát jenom třináct kousků?
Yes.
Ano.
But you know after the thirteenth beer I get really smart.
Ale víš, že po třináctém pivu bývám hrozně chytrej.
We'll manage somehow.
To nějak vydržíme.
Now you, Ivo.
A teď ty, Ivo.
I don't drink beer.
Já pivo nepiju.
But you make phone calls, so I'll buy you a new credit on the first of the month.
Ale telefonuješ, takže ti novej kredit koupím až prvního.
And how are you going to save?
A ty jako budeš šetřit jak?
I'm always saving, otherwise we'd have nothing.
No já šetřím pořád, jinak bysme nic neměli.
This is tyranny.
To je tyranie.
No, this is a crisis.
Ne, to je krize.
They really believe you?
Fakt ti to věřej?
Well, they all have pretty bad eyesight there.
No oni tam všichni dost špatně vidí.
And if someone asked you how old you are?
A kdyby se tě někdo zeptal, kolik ti je?
I'd probably faint.
Tak to bych asi omdlela.
But luckily that's also pretty common there.
Ale to je tam naštěstí taky dost běžný.
What's the point of computer class for seniors anyway?
K čemu ti vůbec je informatika pro seniory?
I like that they talk to us slowly and clearly there.
Mluví se mi, že tam na nás mluví pomalu a zřetelně.
And I'm the best one there.
A jsem tam nejlepší.
Hey, sis.
Hele, segra.
What's that?
Co to je?
My butt.
Můj zadek.
Lexa!
Lexo!
You're taking photos of your butt?
Ty si fotíš zadek?
Obviously.
No jasně.
I've never seen it.
Nikdy jsem ho neviděl.
You photographed it last week.
Ty sis ho fotil minulej týden.
Lexa, lend me that phone.
Lexo, půjč mi ten mobil.
Want to photograph your butt?
Chceš si vyfotit zadek?
No.
Ne.
Want to see mine?
Chceš vidět můj?
I want to send a text.
Chci si poslat SMSku.
That won't work.
To nepůjde.
We can only send one text a year.
My můžeme poslat jenom jednu SMSku ročně.
On Children's Day.
Na den dětí.
To whom?
Komu?
Dad.
Tátovi.
Hi Dad, we love you, don't forget about us.
Ahoj tati, máme tě rádi, nezapomeň na nás.
And the number is on the account.
A číslo máme na účtu.
Damn.
Sakra.
I need to call Voracek right away.
Potřebuju si hned zavolat Voráčkovi.
He's got my Czech notebook.
Má můj sešit z češtiny.
He borrowed your notebook, huh?
Jsi od tebe půjčil sešit, jo?
Is he hitting on you, creep?
Tě balí, hajzle?
First of all.
Přede vším.
I had my tram pass in there.
Měla jsem tam založenou tramvajenku.
With a photo?
S fotkou?
Of course with a photo.
No jasně, že s fotkou.
He's hitting on you?
Tě balí?
Just call him from the landline.
Tak mu zavolej z pevné linky.
You think Dad didn't block calls to cell phones?
Si myslíš, že táta nenechal zablokovat volání na mobily?
I meant to his landline.
Já jsem myslela jako na pevnou.
I already tried.
No, to jsem zkusila.
His mother picked up.
Zvedla to jeho matka.
She interrogated me for half an hour like I was dating Voracek.
Půl hodiny mě vyslýchala, jako kdybych s Voráčkem chodila.
Are you dating him?
A chodíš s ním?
Lexa, go photograph your butt.
Lexo, běž si fotit zadek.
Tomas, come warm up.
Tomáši, pojďte se ohřát.
It's freezing out there, let me tell you.
To je venku, to vám teda řeknu.
I can just picture them at Temelin gloating.
Úplně vidím, jak se v Temelíně tetelí blahem.
Thieves.
Zloději.
It says here they're not thieves.
Tady píšou, že nejsou zloději.
Really?
Vážně?
Who published it?
Kdo to vydal?
CEZ, but with public money, so it must be objective.
No ČEZ, ale za státní peníze, tak to musí být objektivní.
Oh, and what do they say?
Aha, a co píšou?
For example, that given what you pay for electricity, your Life Comfort Index is deeply below normal.
Například, že s tím, co platíte za elektřinu, je váš index komfortu života hluboce pod normálem.
What's the Life Comfort Index?
Co to je index komfortu života?
CEZ came up with it.
S tím přišel ČEZ.
It measures your standard of living by the number of electrical appliances.
Měří se tím životní úroveň podle počtu elektrospotřebičů.
CEZ says for three people it should be nine space heaters, six electric kettles, two washing machines, a fridge, a freezer, a terrarium, and a lathe.
ČEZ říká, že pro tři lidi by to mělo být devět přímotopů, šest rychlovarných konvic, dvě pračky, lednička, mrazák, terárium a soustruh.
So your index is about 0.6.
Takže váš index je tak 0,6.
Well, that seems a bit excessive.
No, to mi připadá trochu přehnané.
Besides, space heaters are money guzzlers.
A navíc přímotopy jsou žrouti peněz.
CEZ recommends space heaters.
ČEZ přímotopy doporučuje.
Gas is dangerous and the price keeps going up.
Plyn je nebezpečný a navíc často zdražuje.
What's that humming?
Co to tady vrní?
The space heater.
No přímotop.
Now?
Teď?
It's cold.
Je zima.
With a six thousand crown surcharge hanging over me, turn it off immediately.
Když mám na krku nedoplatek za šest tisíc, okamžitě to vypněte.
And I don't want you using it here.
A nepřeji si, abyste to tady používala.
Quite possibly you're the one who ran up my bill.
Dost možná, jestli jste mi tu sekeru neudělala vy.
Tomas, this thing is a tiny little thing and it's on the lowest setting.
No Tomáši, teď je to takovýhle drobeček a je na jedničku.
Right, socks.
No vidíte, ponožky.
I'm telling you for the tenth time, I'm perfectly happy with myself.
Říkám ti po desátý, že jsem se sebou naprosto spokojená.
You're not ugly, nobody can say that.
Ošklivá nejsi, to nemůže nikdo říct.
Not outright ugly, but you should do something about yourself.
Vyloženě ošklivá ne, ale něco bys se sebou dělat měla.
Ozzak, knock back that thirteenth beer and shut up, you're always smart as a radio after it.
Ozzáku, kopni do sebe to třináctý pivo a neser, cos po něm vždycky chytrej jak rádio.
Radio Simona, today the world doesn't matter.
Rádio Simona, dneska pro svět není důležitý.
Go on.
Dělej.
I can't!
Nemůžu!
I promised my brother I'd stop after the thirteenth.
Jsem bráchovi slíbil, že budu končit po třináctým.
That brother of yours.
A ten brácha.
He's not stupid.
A on blbej není.
But he just doesn't see some things.
Ale některý věci prostě nevidí.
It's open.
Je otevřeno.
I said it's open.
Jsem říkala, že je otevřeno.
Of what?
Čeho?
May I come in, dearie?
Můžu jít dál, děvenko?
I think they suspect I'm young, so I try to talk like them.
Myslím si, že mě podezřívají, že jsem mladá, tak se snažím mluvit jako oni.
You scared me.
Jsis mě vyděsila.
Sorry.
Promiň.
Let us sit down.
My posadíme se.
Sure.
Jo?
Those stairs wore me out.
Ty schody mi daly zabrat.
Sasa!
Sašo!
Are you in there?
Jsi tam uvnitř?
Come back!
Vrať se!
Sorry.
Promiň.
You know who's in my computer class for seniors?
Víš, kdo se mnou chodí na informatiku pro seniory?
No idea.
Nevím.
Voracek's mom.
Voráčkova máma.
So?
No a?
She was looking up information about you.
Hledala si o tobě informace.
What?
Cože?
Luckily my eyes still work.
Naštěstí mi oči ještě slouží.
Sasa!
Sašo!
Sorry.
Promiň.
I was looking over her shoulder and saw her searching for you in the school database.
Koukala jsem se jí přes rameno a viděla jsem, jak si tě hledá ve školní databázi.
So now she knows where you live.
Takže teď už ví, kde bydlíš.
Damn.
Sakra.
What's that noise?
Co to tady vrčí?
Ivo?
Ivo?
Printing.
Tisknu.
Do you have to have every light on in the apartment for that?
A to si k tomu musíš svítit v celém bytě?
Jesus, I'll turn them off later.
Ježíš, já to pak zhasnu.
And what are you printing?
A tiskneš co?
Bozena Nemcova.
Boženu Němcovou.
The whole thing?
Celou?
Yeah, all of it.
Jo, celou.
And little Bobby.
A malýho Bobše.
And a dictionary too, but that one twice, for me and for Sasa.
A ještě slovník, ale ten dvakrát, pro mě a pro Sašu.
Jesus, come inside and close the door, we don't want to heat the outdoors.
Ježíš, pojď dovnitř a zavři, ať netopíme pánu Bohu do oken.
And don't make light of it.
A ty to nezlehčuj.
I'm not making light of it.
Já to nezlehčuju.
I just waste money, I can't help it, I'm just expensive.
Prostě plýtvám, jinak to neumím, jsem prostě drahá.
And you've got a big butt, you should exercise more.
A máš velkej zadek, měla bys víc cvičit.
You shouldn't nag your brother so much, poor thing.
A ty bys bráchu neměla tolik prudit, chudinku.
A girl isn't a boy, she needs a kind word sometimes too.
Holka není kluk, taky potřebuje občas vlídný slovo.
Keep that in mind, Dad.
Tak na to mysli, táto.
Good morning.
Dobré ráno.
Morning.
Dobrý.
This tea is cold.
Ten čaj je studený.
I had a word with myself.
Šla jsem do sebe.
I'm saving.
Šetřím.
Good.
Dobře.
Or should I heat it up for you?
Nebo ti ho mám ohřát?
No, no, it's refreshing.
Ne, ne, je osvěžující.
These are cold too.
Ty jsou taky studený.
Should they be warm?
Měly by být teplý?
Well, toast could be.
Tak tousty by mohly.
Stick them under your armpits.
Tak si je strč do podpaží.
You're leaving already?
To už jdeš?
Yeah.
Jo.
So I can make it to the school bathroom.
Abych si ve škole stihla skočit na záchod.
At least they have lights there.
Tam se totiž svítí.
Bye.
Tak čau.
I almost forgot my papers.
Málem bych si tu nechala ty papíry.
What is it?
Co je?
Nothing.
Nic.
Oh.
Aha.
Yeah.
Jo.
I turned off the water heater last night.
Včera jsem vypla bojler.
So don't be startled when you shower.
Tak se nelekni, až se budeš sprchovat.
Dad, what was that click?
Tati, co to tu cvaklo?
They don't mean any harm.
Oni to nemyslí zle.
But some things just don't register with them.
Ale některý věci jim prostě nedocházej.
I'm doing this for them.
Vždyť já to dělám pro ně.
You sound like Ozzak after his thirteenth beer.
Mluvíš jako Ozzák po třináctém pivu.
Excuse me.
No dovol.
Am I telling you your nose is crooked?
Říkám ti snad, že máš křivej nos?
You're worse than Ozzak after his thirteenth beer.
Jsi horší než Ozzák po třináctém pivu.
Jesus, I'm sorry.
Ježíš, tak promiň.
I don't accept.
Nepromiňu.
You need to understand that Ozzak has to cut back too.
Musíš pochopit, že se Ozzák taky musí uskrovnit.
And you should understand that a lot of people depend on Ozzak's consumption.
A ty bys měl pochopit, že na Ozzákově spotřebě je závislá spousta lidí.
Want anything else?
Dáš si ještě něco?
What?
Co?
How about some chips.
No tak třeba křupky.
Don't have any.
Nemám.
More wine then.
No tak ještě víno.
All out.
Došlo.
You really won't have anything else?
Opravdu si už nic nedáš?
Jesus, Simona, stop being mad.
Ježíš, Simono, tak už se nezlob.
It's just too much for me.
Je toho prostě na mě moc.
The family's in debt, I do what I can, and they throw sticks under my feet.
Rodina je v dluzích, já dělám, co můžu, a oni mi ještě hážou klacky pod nohy.
95.
95.
What?
Cože?
For a two-liter of wine?
Za dvoulitr vína?
Well, my family is starting to be in debt too, so I'm also doing what I can.
To víš, moje rodina začíná být v dluzích, tak taky dělám, co můžu.
You want to throw sticks under my feet?
Chceš mi házet klacky pod nohy?
You mean those one or two Ozzak beers?
To myslíš to jedno Ozzákovo pivo?
Two.
Dvě.
For yesterday and today.
Za včerejšek a za dnešek.
I'll never save anything this way.
A takhle nic neušetřím.
But I won't be in the red.
Ale já nebudu v mínusu.
And another fifty.
A ještě padesát.
Are you charging admission now?
To jako vybíráš vstupný?
That's for the nose comment.
To je za ten nos.
Give me back the change.
Vrať mi budlík.
That's the admission fee.
To je to vstupný.
It's open.
Je otevřeno.
What do you want?
Co chceš?
Didn't you forget your things here?
Nezapomněla jsi tu svůj grahul?
I didn't.
Nezapomněla.
Oh well.
No jo.
She probably has it at home.
Tu ji má asi doma.
What is it?
Co je?
What are you reading?
Co to čteš?
This started coming with our electricity bills recently.
To nám nedávno začalo chodit s účtama za elektriku.
Flok?
Flok?
What is it?
A co to je?
An adapted edition of Grandmother based on the Life Comfort Index.
Upravené vydání Babičky podle indexu komfortu života.
Grandmother has three blenders and the sultan is a vacuum cleaner.
Babička má tři mixéry a sultán je vysavač.
Oh.
Aha.
The nerve of them sending this to people.
Že se nestyděj tohle posílat lidem.
You're dating Voracek, aren't you?
Chodíš s Voráčkem, že jo?
Am I stupid?
Jsem blbá?
Don't lie!
Nelži!
Have you lost your mind?
Ty jsi se zbláznil?
I saw you two perfectly well standing together in front of the school.
Já jsem vás moc dobře viděl před školou, jak jste stáli spolu.
Jesus, Lexa, he was returning my notebook.
Ježíš, Lexo, vracel mi sešit.
Yeah, and why did you go to the park then?
Jo, a proč jste pak šli do parku?
You were following me?
Ty jsi mě sledoval?
Yeah.
Jo.
Have you totally lost it?
Ti normálně hráblo?
Why did you go to the park?
Proč jste šli do toho parku?
Lexa, calm down for God's sake.
Lexo, uklidni se, proboha.
We walked through the park to Voracek's house for the tram pass.
Šli jsme přes park k Voráčkovi domů pro tu tramvajenku.
That idiot dropped it from the notebook.
Tomu kreténovi vypadla ze sešitu.
You were at his house?
Ty jsi byla u něj doma?
Lexa, listen to me carefully.
Lexo, dobře mě poslouchej.
Voracek is a moron.
Voráček je debil.
And I would never date him.
A nikdy bych s ním nechodila.
Great.
Super.
Which also applies to you.
Což platí i o tobě.
Still great.
Stejně super.
Ivo, do you know some Voracek?
Ivo, prosím tě, ty znáš nějakýho Voráčka?
What?
Co?
His mother just called and invited me for coffee, saying it's about time we got to know each other.
Teď mi volala jeho matka a zvala mě na kafe, že prý už je na čase, abychom se seznámili.
Do you know what that's about?
Nevíš, co to má znamenat?
Jesus Christ.
Ježíši Kriste.
What was that?
Co to bylo?
I have no idea.
Vůbec nevím.
Everyone's acting like lunatics.
Všichni se chovají jako blázni.
Tell me about it.
No to mi povídej.
Well look, it's not overheated in here today.
No vida, dneska tady není přetopeno.
Good evening, Tomas.
Dobrý večer, Tomáši.
That really wasn't necessary.
Tak to snad nebylo nutné.
There's sixty in there.
Je tam šedesátka.
What were the sales?
Jaká byla tržba?
Zero.
Žádná.
Nobody came in again?
To tu zas nikdo nebyl?
No.
Ne.
You don't say.
No to mi neříkejte.
There was one strange person, but she didn't buy anything.
No byla tady jedna taková divná osoba, ale nic si nekoupila.
Ozzak.
Ozzák.
He called saying he'd be in the pub all day so he wouldn't waste heat for nothing.
Ten volal, že bude dneska celý den v hospodě, aby zbůhdarma nevysával teplo.
This was the mother of one of Ivo's classmates.
Tohle byla matka někoho od Ivy ze školy.
Was it by any chance Vorackova?
Nebyla to náhodou Voráčková?
You know her?
Vy ji znáte?
She was asking really strange questions.
Ona se totiž opravdu tak divně vyptávala.
About what?
A na co?
Whether you own this place or rent it, and how much it brings in.
No jestli vám to tady patří, nebo jestli jste v nájmu, a kolik vám to vynáší.
What?
Cože?
Don't worry, I didn't tell her anything, not even your cell number.
Nebojte se, já jsem jí nic neřekla, ani číslo vašeho mobilu.
But I took her business card.
Ale vzala jsem si vizitku.
I'm going to have a word with that woman, she won't like it.
S tou ženskou si promluvím, ta si to za rámeček nedá.
Off you go, Marcelka, I'll close up here.
Tak už běžte, Marcelko, já to tady zavřu.
I'll just sit here a while longer.
Já si to ještě posedím.
Well, you know.
No, to víte.
That nasty weather out there.
Ten nečas tam venku.
Overall, it's kind of warm in here.
No celkově, tady je u vás nějak teplo.
What's this cable here?
Co je to tady za kabel?
Marcelka!
Marcelko!
I hate socks!
Já nesnáším ponožky!
What would you like, granny?
Copak byste ráda, babičko?
Lexa went to fight Voracek.
Lexa se šel porvat s Voráčkem.
How do you know?
Jak to víš?
He wrote you a farewell letter.
Napsal ti dopis na rozloučenou.
I am writing to you, what more can I do?
Já píšu vám, co mohu více?
I had to copy it out of Onegin for him.
Musela jsem to pro něj vypsat z Oněgina.
I'm worried about him.
Mám o něj strach.
About Lexa?
O Lexu?
About Voracek.
O Voráčka.
Lexa took a cactus with him.
Lexa si s sebou vzal kaktus.
A cactus?
Kaktus?
He was looking for something sharp at home, he was furious.
Hledal doma něco ostrýho, byl strašně naštvaný.
Don't worry.
Neboj.
He's a hothead, acts first and thinks later.
Je to horká hlava, nejdřív jedná a pak myslí.
Voracek?
Voráček?
Lexa.
Lexa.
Yeah, Lexa only acts.
Jo, Lexa vlastně jenom jedná.
Voracek too, actually.
Voráček vlastně taky.
What if they hurt each other?
Co když si něco udělaj?
What if they do something with that cactus?
A co když něco udělaj s tím kaktusem?
What a day.
To je den.
I've got no phone, I can't take a bath, I can't read, and on top of it two morons are fighting because of me.
Jsem bez telefonu, koupat se nesmím, na čtení nevidím a ještě si kvůli mně perou dva debilové.
You should finally choose between them, dearie.
Měla bys se mezi nima konečně vybrat, děvenko.
How is it possible that these numbers are so high?
Jak je možný, že ty cifry jsou nějak tak velký?
Well, look here.
No podívejte.
Bring it closer to the lamp.
Dejte to k tý lampičce blíž.
Here, April 2009, 1,500.
Tady, duben 2009, 1500.
And April 2010, 2,500.
A duben 2010, 2500.
When did you start heating?
Kdy jste začala topit?
I don't know, November.
Já nevím, v listopadu.
That doesn't add up.
Tak to mi nehraje.
I'm going home.
Jdu domů.
What, now?
Cože, teď?
I'm cold.
Je mi zima.
Either light or heat.
Buď světlo nebo teplo.
And we need light.
A světlo potřebujeme.
I'm going home!
Jdu domů!
I didn't say that much.
Tak zas jsem toho tolik neřek.
You told me to put on thick socks.
Řek, abych si vzala tlustý ponožky.
Because you keep complaining you're cold.
Protože si pořád stěžujete, že je vám zima.
But it is cold in here.
Ale je tady zima.
For three hours I've been helping you find proof that I burned through millions with this pathetic little heater and this blanket.
Už tři hodiny vám pomáhám hledat důkaz, že jsem tady tím ubohým fukárkem a touhle dečkou protopila miliony.
And you won't even let me turn on the heat.
A vy mi ani nedovolíte zatopit.
Alright, turn it on for a bit.
Dobře, tak si to na chvilku zapněte.
No, I'm going home!
Ne, jdu domů!
You're just going to leave me here alone?
A to mě v tom jako necháte samotnýho?
You should have thought of that before you took my blanket.
To jste si měl rozmyslet, než jste mi vzal dečku.
Great that you're coming.
Skvělý, že jdete.
You can examine the bills with your brother until morning.
Můžete tady s bratrem zkoumat účty až do rána.
You're not a bad woman, Marcelka, but you're a terrible judge of character.
Nejste zlá ženská, Marcelko, ale máte blbej odhad na lidi.
Shut up!
Sklapni!
General fear of wild animals.
Celkově strach z divokých zvířat.
But frozen ones!
Ale ze zmrzlých!
They're thieves.
To jsou zloději.
What?
Cože?
They raised your rate.
Tady vám zvedli tarif.
Give it here.
Dejte to sem.
Right, we had the comfort plan.
No jo, měli jsme komfort.
And now we have the low-heating plan.
A teď máme topíme málo.
And here the kilowatts are more expensive, much more.
A tady jsou dražší kilowatty, a o dost.
Are you kidding me?
Děláte si srandu?
No.
Ne.
The less you use, the more you pay.
Čím míň spotřebujete, tím víc zaplatíte.
That's logical.
To je logické.
But on the bright side, they're giving away a free energy edition of Czech classics.
No ale zase, tady dávají zdarma energetickou edici českých klasiků.
I'll tell you how it is, bro.
Já ti, brácho, řeknu, jak to je.
Look, Ozzak, go to the pub and have your fourteenth beer.
Hele, Ozzáku, běž do hospody a dej si čtrnáctý pivo.
Thanks.
Dík.
And you, turn on the heat.
A vy zatopte.
Well, what are you waiting for?
No na co čekáte?
And set it to three.
A dejte to na trojku.
It only goes up to two.
Tady je jenom dvojka.
I said set it to three.
Řekl jsem na trojku.
I don't want to change.
Nechci se převlíct.
Because I'd have to get up.
Když to bych musela vstávat.
Sis.
Segra.
Give me the keys.
Dej mi klíče.
Lexa, how did it go?
Lexo, jak to dopadlo?
Where's your cactus?
Kde máš kaktus?
My cactus.
Můj kaktus.
Won't you sit down?
Neposadíš se?
I'll wait.
Čekám.
Here are the tweezers.
Jo, tady máš tu pinzetu.
Thanks.
Dík.
So, what did you need them for?
No, co jsi ji potřeboval?
Don't talk about it!
Nebavte se o tom!
If you weren't stupid, you could be sitting on something soft.
Kdybys nebyl blbej, mohl jsi sedět na měkkém.
You really won't tell me what happened?
Fakt mi neřekneš, co se stalo?
Voracek shoved my cactus down the back of his pants.
Voráček mu strčil můj kaktus zezadu do kalhot.
Sis, you're a chicken!
Segra, ty seš slepice!
Yeah, and you destroyed my cactus!
Jo, a ty jsi mi zničil kaktus!
Voracek destroyed it!
Voráček ti ho zničil!
If you hadn't sat on it and pulled the cactus out, nothing would've happened!
Kdybys na něj nesedal a ten kaktus si vyndal, tak se nic nestalo!
I was in the middle of beating him up!
Vždyť jsem mu zrovna dával nakládačku!
What is it?
Co je?
Take a photo of it.
Vyfoť mi to.
Ivo, I'm going to sort things out with Mrs. Vorackova.
Ivo, jdu se zkusit vyřídit s paní Voráčkovou.
You're meeting with Vorackova?
Ty se stýkáš s Voráčkovou?
We had coffee together.
Byli jsme spolu na kafi.
I hope for the last time.
Doufám, že naposled.
Did you have to pay?
Musel jsi platit?
That too.
To taky.
We agreed that whatever you have going on with that Voracek has to end!
Domluvili jsme se, že to, co máš s tím Voráčkem, musí skončit!
Jesus, I've got nothing going on with him!
Ježíš, já s ním nic nemám!
I would hope so.
To bych ti teda radil.
Did he take the photo yet?
Už si udělal tu fotku?
That's enough.
Tak dost.
You're not old enough to be turning boys' heads.
Na to, abys chlapcům pletla hlavu, ještě nemáš věk.
The poor boy stuck some spines into himself in a panic.
Vždyť ten nebohý hoch si do sebe kulitově zapíchal nějaké ostny.
My cactus.
Můj kaktus.
Fine, I'll leave Voracek alone then, okay?
Dobře, tak já teda nechám Voráčka na pokoji, hm?
She's finally come to her senses.
Konečně dostala rozum.
Alright, please, when you get home, run the washing machine once more, even empty.
Tak jo, prosím tě, až přijdeš domů, tak ještě pusť pračku jednou, klidně naprázdno.
Even empty.
Klidně naprázdno.
And don't be startled, I left the vacuum running.
A nelekni se, nechal jsem zapnutý lux.
Simona, set the table quick before it gets cold.
Simono, rychle prostírej, ať nám nevystydne.
Did you bake this in the storeroom?
To jsi pekla v kumbále?
No, on the electric.
Ne, na elektrice.
Excellent.
Výborně.
Dad.
Tati.
We're chasing the comfort index.
Honíme komfort.
That brother of mine, he's such a good person.
Ten brácha, to je tak hodnej člověk.
Patient, without a mean bone in his body.
Trpělivý, nezáludnej.
He takes care of me like his own.
Stará se o mě jako o vlastního.
You are his own.
Jseš vlastní.
But I don't act like it!
Ale nechovám se tak!
I cause trouble!
Zlobím!
I don't go to work and when I do, I don't do anything!
Do práce nechodím a když chodím, nic nedělám!
I drink!
Chlastám!
I don't pay!
Neplatím!
You know?
Víš?
I know.
Vím.
Ivuska.
Ivuška.
Yeah, Ivuska.
No, Ivuška.
What kind of childhood does she have when she has to take care of me?
Co ona z toho dětství má, když se musí starat o mě?
She cleans for me, she'd love to do my laundry!
Uklízí mi, tak ráda by mi prala!
And me?
A já?
No, and no, and no!
Ne, a ne, a ne!
I won't let her!
A nechci jí to dovolit!
Poor girl.
Chudák holka.
And I even told her she has a big butt.
A ještě jsem jí řekl, že má velkej zadek.
She doesn't.
Nemá.
She does, but you don't say that!
No má, ale to se přece neříká!
Ugh, Ozzak!
Fuj, Ozzák!
Ozzak, please, won't you finally finish that fifteenth one?
Ozzáku, prosím tě, nechceš už to patnáctý konečně dopít?
You're sick of me too, aren't you?
Ty už mě máš taky plný zuby, viď?